Based on the true story of the King of Salsa, Hector Lavoe
El Cantante is a history, drama, music film directed by Leon Ichaso.
The rise and fall of salsa singer, Héctor Lavoe (1946-1993), as told from
the perspective of his wife Puchi, who looks back from 2002.
Hector Lavoe, played by Marc Anthony.
Puchi, played by Jennifer Lopez.
Willie Colon, played by John Ortiz.
Eddie, played by Manny Perez.
Ralph, played by Vincent Laresca.
Jerry Masucci, played by Federico Castelluccio.
El Cantante (The Singer) is a 2006 biographical film which
stars singers Marc Anthony and Jennifer Lopez.
The film is based on the life of the late salsa singer
Héctor Lavoe, who is portrayed by Anthony.
The film is told from the viewpoint of Puchi, Hector's wife, portrayed by Lopez.
Initially debuting at the Toronto International Film Festival on
September 12, 2006, El Cantante was released on August 3, 2007.
Distributed by Picturehouse, the film runs for 106 minutes and
is rated R for language, sexuality and drug use.
According to Box Office Mojo, El Cantante is the twenty-eighth
highest-grossing musical biopic of all time.
The film explores themes of dancing, 1970s, blunt, salsa, dramatic.
The tone is emotional.